Like Diane said a unit of diversion is how we define what an individual subject
如 Diane 所说 实验中的分组单元
is in the experiment.
是用来定义个体对象的途径
There are three commonly used categories of unit of diversion.
常用分组单元有三种
The first two a user identifier and an anonymous identifier are different
前两个是用户标识和匿名标识 这两者是不同的
approximations for an actual user or person.
它们近似于实际用户或个人
And the last is just the single event.
最后一个为单一事件
Let's dive into each of these.
我们来进一步了解每一种分组单元
A user identifier is what most people think of first for
人们首先会想借用户标识
running an experiment on.
做实验
This would be something like the login that people create on websites or apps.
它就像人们在网站或应用软件上注册的登录名
For example, your email address if you log into Facebook or
比如 登录 Facebook 或 Amazon 时输入的
Amazon, or your username, if create a username instead.
邮件地址或用户名
While a person could have more than one login, typically a login
尽管某人可以有一个以上的登录名 一般来说
is a pretty good proxy for a user and it's stable and unchanging.
登录名是不错的用户代理 而且它稳定不变
If you use a user id as your unit of diversion, what that means is that all
如果你把用户 ID 作为分组单元 就意味着
the events correspond to the same used id are either in the control group or
所有事件都对应着对照组或实验组中的同一个用户 ID
the experiment group, but they are not mixed between the two groups.
而不同组之间不会混淆
Whether the user is using an app on their phone,
不管用户在使用手机应用
visiting the website on their phone, or
还是用手机访问网站
visiting the website on their desktop computer, it's a consistent experience.
或在台式电脑上访问网站 体验都是一致的
However, it's worth noting that a user id is considered personally
但值得注意的是 用户 ID 仅为
identifiable.
个人标识
Some sites use your email address as your login and for
一些网址使用邮件地址作登录名
sites where you create a username many people use some variation on their name.
还有一些网站让人们创建各种名称变体为用户名
And either way the site will typically associate some other information with
不管名称如何 网站一般会将其它信息关联到此帐户
the account, such as the user's email address or phone number,
比如用户邮箱或手机号
to help with account recovery.
以便找回帐户
An anonymous id is usually something like a cookie.
一个匿名 ID 常与 cookie 相似
On most websites, whenever a user visits the website, it will write a cookie,
只要用户访问 大多网站都会为用户写一个 cookie
which is usually an anonymous random identifier to a file on that device.
它常作为设备上某文件的匿名随机标识
The cookie is specific to a browser and a device though.
而这个 cookie 仅属于一个浏览器和一个设备
If the users switches from Chrome to Firefox, or if
如果用户从 Chrome 转向 Firefox
they switch from their laptop to their phone, they'll get a different cookie.
或从笔记本换为手机 他们会得到与之前不同的 cookie
Users can also choose to clear their cookies, in which case the next time
用户也可清除 cookie 这样下一次访问此网址时
they visit the website they'll get assigned a new one.
用户会获得的一个新的 cookie
It's also possible to set your preferences such that every time you
用户也可以设置偏好 比如每次关闭浏览器
close your browser, all your cookies are cleared automatically.
浏览器会自动清除所有 cookie
In other words, it's much easier for a person to change their cookie
也就是说比起更改或注销帐户 即用户标识
than it is for a person to change or clear an account, ie a user identifier.
改变 cookie 更容易
Apps on mobile devices can also use a similar cookie mechanism.
移动设备上的应用也会使用相似的 cookie 机制
Although it can be a bit more cumbersome to clear a cookie on a mobile device or
尽管清除移动设备或应用中的 cookie
for an app than it is in a browser.
比清除浏览器的 cookie 更麻烦些
Finally, event-based diversion means that on every single event,
最终 基于事件的分组意味着 对每一次事件
you redecide whether that event is in the experiment or in the control.
你得重新判断它是在实验组还是对照组
This means that a user may not get a consistent experience at all, so
这意味着用户无法获得一致的体验
this is only appropriate in situations where the changes are not user visible.
只有在用户不可见更改的情况下才妥当
For example, if you have a ranked list,
比如 你对排序列表的顺序做出了更改
changes to the order of the list would fall in this category.
就符合这种情况
Most users can't tell or won't notice.
大多用户无法区分或察觉排序变化
There are also a couple of other less commonly used options for
还有一些是不太常用的
unit of diversion.
分组单元
On mobile devices only, there's an option called a device id that's
仅限移动设备的一种选择为设备 ID
in between a cookie and a user ID.
它介于 cookie 和用户 ID 之间
The device device id is typically something that's
设备 ID 一般是指
tied to a specific device, and it's unchangeable by the user.
用户绑定到特定设备并不再变更的内容
It's also considered identifiable because it's immutable.
它也被认为是可识别的 因为它不可变的特性
But it doesn't have the cross device or
但它不具有跨设备或跨平台的一致性
cross platform consistency that the user identifier might have.
而用户识别符却有
Another option is to divert based on IP address, so
另一种分组方案是基于 IP 地址的分组
that any event with the same IP address will be put in the same group.
IP 地址相同的事件会划分在同一组
If the user changes location, then they often get a new IP address.
如果用户变更登录地点 他们往往会得到一个新 IP 地址
To make sure all this is clear, I'll go through an example.
为了说明白 我要举个例子
Imagine you have a user who does the following sequence of events.
假如你的用户 按如下顺序的事件操作
They're on desktop, not signed in, and they visit the homepage.
在台式电脑 他们未登录网站便访问了主页
They've also cleared their cookies recently.
他们近期还清除过 cookie
So they're not automatically signed in.
所以不会自动登录
So, they sign in again, then they visit a class,
所以 再次登录后他们访问了一节课程
and then they start watching a video.
之后开始观看视频
After that video, we don't see the user again for a while, but
视频之后 一段时间内没有看见用户再活动
then they pop up on their mobile phone where they're automatically signed in
但之后他们在手机端自动登录
because the login is saved.
因为登录名已保存
Then they continue watching the video from where they stopped last.
然后他们从上次暂停处继续观看视频
Now suppose you're running an experiment that would affect
现在假如你的实验会影响
each of these different pages.
其中每个页面
For example, maybe you changed something about the navigation bar and
比如 也许你更改了导航栏
it shows up on every page.
它在每个页面上都有显示
For each of the different units of diversion we've talked about, user-id,
对每一个所提及的分组单元
cookie, event, device id and
如用户 ID、cookie、事件、设备 ID 和 IP 地址
IP address, when would the user be assigned to the same group as before and
用户在何种情况下组别保持不变？
when could they potentially be switched to the other group?
何种情况又可能被换到另一组？
That is, the experimental group if they were in the control and vice-versa.
就是说 何时会从对照组换到实验组 或相反
For each case, check the box at the point or points,
在这些案例中 如果用户从实验组变为对照组或反之
where the user could be switched from the experiment to control or vice-versa,
包括他们第一次分配至某一组
including the first time that they are assigned to a group.
勾选该方框
For the IP address diversion, you don't haven't enough information to answer.
对 IP 地址的分组 你没有充足信息判断
Clearly, they'll be assigned to a group when they first visit, but
显然 首次访问时他们会被分配到一组
after that their IP Address could change at any point and
之后的 IP 地址随时可能改变
if it does, they could be reassigned.
改变后它们有会被重新分配